Guide to the Helen Sewell papers,[ca. 1930-1955]
Sewell, Helen papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Helen Sewell papers, [ca. 1930-1955]
6616
Helen, Sewell 1896-
5 cubic ft.
Artwork, correspondence, photographs,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence with publishers, other letters, photographs, and original illustrations and artwork for her cards and books.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Illustrator.
Helen Moore Sewell, the daughter of William Elbridge Sewell and Minnie Moore, was born into a Navy family and spent part of her early years in Japan and Guam. She attended the Pratt Institute and studied painting with the artist Archipenko. She worked on Christmas and greeting cards, and illustrated many books, particularly for children. She was the original illustrator for the "Little House" books by Laura Ingalls Wilder. She later wrote and illustrated her own books for children.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence with publishers, other letters, photographs, and original illustrations and artwork for her cards and books.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Sewell, Helen,1896-
Subjects:
Children's books--History--United States--20th century.; Picture books for children--Publishing--United States.; Illustrators--United States.; Children's literature--Illustrations.; Picture books.; Illustrators.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Publisher Correspondence, 1935-1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Publisher Agreements and Contracts, 1935-1954 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Royalty Statements, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Estate Records, 1957-1960 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Simon & Schuster and Scribner's Documents, 1958-1994 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Royalty Claims and Correspondence between Patricia Hill and MacMillian Publishing, 1990-1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence with Family (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence with Susanne Lauger, 1920-1941 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Misc. Correspondence, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence with Patricia Cautley, 1936-1943 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
- Misc. Book Information and Correspondence, 1950s-1960s (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Misc. Correspondence, 1911-1952 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Misc. Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Misc. Correspondence, Articles, and Photos (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Helen Sewell Curriculum Vitae, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Helen Sewell Photos (baby to adult) and review from the New Yorker (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Helen Sewell Photographs (all ages), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Misc. Publications and Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Publications and Photos of Helen Sewell Illustrations, 1930-1946 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- American Artist Magazine with Helen Sewell Feature, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Photos of Ink Drawings, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Christmas Card Illustations, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Manuscripts for "Patience is a Virtue" and the "Village of Peace and Happiness" (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Misc. Photos, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Copy of "Belinda and the Mouse" and the Hornbook Magazine, 1944, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Illustrations for "Blue Bonnets for Lucinda" (Box 1, Folder 27-28)
- Copy of "Building a House in Sweden", 1931 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Helen Sewell's New York City Contacts (index cards) (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Metal Stamp of Helen Sewell Illustration, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Interview of Patricia Hill by K. Gauley (cassette tape), 1987 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Helen Sewell Interview with Alice Duubay (cassette tape), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Sense and Sensibility study drawings (Box 1, Folder 34)
- "A First Bible" illustrations (Box 2, Folder 1)
- "A Head for Happy" illustrations (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
- "Azor and the Blue-Eyed Cow" illustrations (Box 2, Folder 4)
- "Azor and the Haddock" illustrations (Box 2, Folder 5)
- "The Bears on Hemlock Mountain" illustrations (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
- "Blue Barns" illustrations (Box 2, Folder 8)
- "Brave Bantam" illustrations and sketches (Box 2, Folder 9)
- "Dream Keeper" illustrations (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Fishermen illustrations (Box 2, Folder 11)
- "Jane Eyre" illustrations (Box 3, Folder 1)
- "Jimmy and Jemima" illustrations (Box 3, Folder 2)
- "Once There Was a Little Boy" illustrations (Box 3, Folder 3)
- "Sense and Sensibility" illustrations (Box 3, Folder 4)
- "Tag Along Too Loo" illustrations (Box 4, Folder 1)
- "Three Tall Tales" illustrations (Box 4, Folder 2-4)
- Misc. Illustrations (Box 4, Folder 5-7)
- Misc. Ink Drawings and Illustrations (Box 5, Folder 1-9)
- "In the Beginning" illustrations (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
- "Pride and Prejudice" illustrations (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
- "Tag Along Too Loo" illustrations (Box 7, Folder 3-7)
- "A Round of Carols", Undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
- "Azor", Undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
- "Azor and the Blue-eyed Cow", Undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
- "Azor and the Haddock", Undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
- "Emily Dickenson", Undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
- "Emily Dickenson" 2, Undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
- "Three Kings of Saba", Undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
- "Wrinkles Went Riding", Undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Untitled, Undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Misc. Ink Drawings (Folder 1-2)
- Misc. Paintings (Folder 3-6)
- Misc. Illustrations (Folder 7)
- "Jane Eyre" illustrations (Folder 8)